♪ In the not too distant
Future ♪
♪ Next Sunday AD ♪
♪ There was a guy named Joel ♪
♪ Not too different
From you or me ♪
♪ He worked at
Gizmonic Institute ♪
♪ Just another face
In a red jumpsuit ♪
♪ He did a good job
Cleaning up the place ♪
♪ But his bosses
Didn't like him ♪
♪ So they shot him into space ♪
♪ We'll send him cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst we can find
La la la ♪
♪ He'll have to sit
And watch them all ♪
♪ And we'll monitor his mind
La la la ♪
♪ Now keep in mind
Joel can't control ♪
♪ Where the movies begin or end
La-la-la ♪
♪ Because he used those
Special parts ♪
♪ To make his robot friends ♪
♪ Robot roll call ♪
♪ Cambot! ♪
- ♪ Pan left ♪
- ♪ Gypsy! ♪
- ♪ Hi girl! ♪
- ♪ Tom Servo! ♪
- ♪ What a cool guy ♪
- ♪ Croooow! ♪
- ♪ Wisecracker ♪
♪ If you're wondering
How he eats and breathes ♪
♪ And other science facts
La la la ♪
♪ Then repeat to yourself ♪
♪ "It's just a show
I should really just relax" ♪
♪ For Mystery
Science Theater 3000 ♪
- Oh Larry, I brought you
a little something
from the mad scientist
convention this year.
Little gift,
little tchotchke for you.
- Oh, what is it, you?
- It's the Isaac Asimov
body splash.
It's part of the foundation
trilogy gift set.
- Oh, and it's pretty too.
It smells like space!
- Yes, and it also goes
with the mad scientist
masculine hygiene...
- Oh, let me try that!
- Later, later.
It's time to get Joel
on the old horn here,
give him our experiment
this week.
Would you like
to do the honors?
- Oh, you are
something special.
[GASPS]
[GRUNTS]
Come in, Joel,
you tree rotating skanky boy.
- Not bad, not bad.
- Hey, sirs.
Hey, Cambot,
bring it in a little bit.
I'm ready for this week's
invention exchange.
This is called
the Cairo-Gyro
and if you happen to suffer
from back, neck, or pelvis pain,
you strap it on
and let it go.
It does the work for you,
watch.
What do you think?
- Mmm.
I'd like to strap
that on you, Larry.
- Yeah, that'd be
a nice way to unwind.
[GIGGLES]
- Oh, stop it.
- I'm sorry.
- Here's our invention
this week, Joelette.
As you know, the old
squirting joke flower
has lost its ability
to shock or surprise.
- We souped it up though.
We came up with
the burning boutonniere
featuring the flame-flower.
- I'd like to see anyone
that isn't surprised
by that, Joelenne.
Yes.
[LAUGHING]
- I cannot believe you guys.
That is so hateful.
BOTH:
Thank you!
- Well, our burnt offering
this week, Joel,
is a little scientific nugget
called The Corpse Vanishes.
- It features Bela Lugosi
stewing in his own mediocrity.
- Yes, but first another one
of those space stinkers,
Commando Cody
and the Bridge of Death.
- Enjoy.
[BUZZER]
- Movie sign!
[♪♪♪]
TOM:
Another republic cereal?
JOEL:
Yeah, used to my head-cranker.
I showed it to the professors.
CROW:
How'd they like it?
JOEL:
I think they liked it.
And they had this
flame-flower thing,
it was very weird.
TOM:
Radar men from the moon!
They liked
the head-cranker, huh?
George Wallace,
Aline Towne, Roy Barcroft,
William Bakewell,
Clayton Moore.
With Peter Brocco,
Bob Stevenson, Don Walters,
Tom Steele, Dale Van Sickel,
Wilson Wood, Noel Cravat,
Baynes Barron,
Paul McGuire, Ted Thorpe,
♪ And written by
Ronald Davidson ♪
♪ John MacBurnie, Fred A... ♪
JOEL:
Okay, that's good. That's fine.
CROW:
Make him read the small print.
JOEL:
Yeah, what's that symbol
mean over there?
I always wondered about it.
TOM: It means Golden Club.
JOEL:
Golden Club turkey?
TOM: Uh, yes.
JOEL: Okay.
TOM:
This is in fact a Golden Club
turkey of a movie.
Chapter Three,
Bridge of Death.
CROW:
I think it's about dentistry.
JOEL:
Yeah.
CROW:
Hey, how come Ted's so big
and Commando Cody
is so small?
JOEL:
Oh Crow, that's a common
movie device
called foreshortening.
CROW:
Oh.
JOEL:
Yeah, they use it all the time.
CROW:
Instead of butter.
TOM:
That's like someone's
throwing their [indistinct] up.
JOEL:
It's a Whamo Magic Window.
TOM:
Evil [indistinct] men
continued to use
the constant heat ray,
which sounded like
a Chevy horn.
CROW:
Hey, surf's up!
- Whoa, maybe we can
get out along that side.
- What about that tank?
- We may be able
to take care of it.
JOEL:
What about the camera crew?
TOM:
They were annihilated,
the entire crew
was annihilated.
But they got the shot.
JOEL:
Flash him,
he's got his high beams on.
CROW:
The blood stream.
- Let's try this one.
CROW:
Quick, up this hill.
Try not to look like
Mr. Peanut.
JOEL:
Or Mr. Salty.
CROW:
Or Mr. Drip.
TOM:
Or Mr. Bubble.
- Give me a hand grenade.
TOM:
Hand grenade?
CROW:
Hand grenade.
TOM:
Eat shrapnel tire, boys.
JOEL:
Boy, that really hurt 'em.
- He must've gotten off.
- Let's move out of here.
CROW:
What a couple of retreads.
Remember, signal your intent,
use your mirrors,
put it in reverse,
mind your space cushion.
TOM:
Space cushion?
CROW:
It's what they're sitting on.
- That does it, Ted.
Let's get back
to the rocket ship.
TOM: Okay.
JOEL: Don't bang into anything.
TOM:
Meanwhile...
- Too bad
you lost that ray gun.
JOEL:
Jim never drinks coffee
on our home planet.
- ...of getting one.
We couldn't possibly
attack their city
with any of our weapons.
- That isn't the worst of it.
They've already tracked us
halfway to the ship,
so they know about
where we are.
CROW:
Spacemen just don't look
at home in a breakfast nook.
- One blast from that ray gun
will pop this ship
like a toy balloon.
- Maybe we'd better
get back to earth.
JOEL:
What do you think, mmm?
- I think so.
We've accomplished the most
important part of our mission.
We discovered
that Redick
is planning to lead
an invasion from the moon
as soon as the saboteurs
finish opening up our defenses.
And it's up to us to get
the information back to earth.
How soon can we take off?
- Well, I've gotta
build up the pressure
in all the tanks
and warm up the jets.
Maybe a couple of hours.
- Then get started.
I'll fly out and scout around
until you're ready.
CROW:
Oh, and the woman
will clean up.
How progressive.
[TOM HUMMING]
Uh?
Mmm.
That's not one of ours.
Hmm, I'd better-- hmm.
CROW:
Hey Joel,
what's that he's cranking?
JOEL:
I think it's
some kind of radio.
TOM:
It's his crotch mounted
cordless phone.
JOEL:
That guy's speaking
into a cruller.
CROW:
Maybe he's Danish.
TOM:
If it's the moon,
it's a cheese Danish.
- ...our scout car
was attacked.
- Splendid.
I'll send another car out
after it at once.
Stay there and keep watch.
- Yes, sir.
JOEL:
Hiiiiiiii!
Oh, my shoes are untied.
CROW:
He's wearing
hand thrown pottery.
My suit's more comfortable
and I'm willing
to fight about it.
TOM:
Our own Commando Cody
is wearing a stylish frock
with metallic pointed,
almost gothic styling.
His power things
are very flattering,
never ever making him
look pudgy of bloated.
Mr. Crow?
CROW: Thank you.
Mr. X, on the other hand,
is wearing a white
cotton space-shift
with almost
a nymph-like quality to it.
It is belted and gathered
at the joints
to give it
a lighter than air feel.
You too can feel one sixth
your own weight
in this space-shift by Dundee.
JOEL:
Alien train supplied by Tyco.
TOM:
Oh, he didn't come
out of his tuck in time.
CROW:
I'll take that, Mr. Bond.
TOM:
Nipple, nipple, tweak, tweak,
fly, fly, fly!
JOEL:
Oh I hate that,
my shoe's still untied.
CROW:
How come he doesn't land
on his head?
JOEL:
He knows better.
TOM:
He'd stick there
like a lawn dart.
- ...found our ship.
I took care of him,
but I'm afraid
he already reported us.
How much longer
before we can take off?
- One of those tanks
is headed this way!
- How 'bout it, Hank?
- I won't guarantee the results
but we can try.
Here it goes, all jets.
CROW:
Well, one jet.
JOEL:
Here it comes.
- Looks like we may make it.
- If we get out of range
of their ray gun in time.
- Shut off
that induction valve!
CROW: Fire in the hole.
JOEL: We're hit!
Everybody lean.
TOM:
Medic, oh!
Looks like
the Macy Parade gone awry.
- Particulate compartments.
- Right.
TOM:
Kablooey.
CROW:
Taking a lot of flack.
JOEL:
Kind of reminds me of Das Boot.
- Looks like
we're in the clear.
TOM: Das "Moon" Boot.
JOEL: Yeah.
- Things are sort of
messed up in there,
but nothing serious.
CROW:
Just everything's broken.
- Okay, Hank.
You can start
for the Earth now.
Make a 180 degree turn.
TOM: 180 degrees?
JOEL: For savings!
[CROW HOWLS LIKE A WOLF]
[♪♪♪]
- Very well.
TOM:
A princess phone, how cute.
- Patrol car reported
that the spaceship has escaped.
- Ship must not be allowed
to land on Earth.
JOEL:
Set it for stun.
CROW:
Why does the Earth
have a shadow?
TOM:
Why are there clouds in space?
CROW:
Why are we watching this?
TOM:
Daddy, what's Vietnam?
JOEL:
I told you
to never call me here.
- ...rocket ship has escaped
and is headed back to Earth.
He has all the information
about our planned invasion
and must not be allowed
to tell it to the authorities.
Will you have a ray gun
completed by the time he lands?
- I'm afraid that is
impossible, Your Excellency.
CROW:
All the hardware stores
are closed.
- That ship must be destroyed
before anyone can get out of it.
JOEL:
Set that on stun.
- You heard the orders.
- Yeah,
but it might not be that easy.
There might be guards
at the landing field.
- Nevertheless, you will
carry out instructions.
I will furnish you
with a bomb.
You can devise some means
for placing it
under the ship
the moment it lands.
- How do we know
when they'll get here?
- I'll pick up their approach
on my radar.
You can be in position
when they land.
JOEL:
I can't believe those thugs
are taking orders from
a guy dressed in spandex.
CROW:
Eh.
Hey, great spot for a picnic.
Did you bring the basket?
TOM:
Yeah, I brought it.
Fried chicken, right?
CROW:
Crouch down like me.
JOEL:
We supposed to run
like this the whole way?
CROW:
Yeah.
JOEL:
Couple of dumb cops.
- Yes. Got to blast 'em.
TOM:
There's gum under this one.
- ...get out of the ship.
- Here she comes.
JOEL:
Look at the lines
on that beauty.
- Coming in for a landing.
JOEL:
Just keep turning
and switching knobs
'til we get her down.
- Calling landing fields.
Calling landing fields.
- Landing fields
to rocket, come in.
- We're coming down.
Field clear?
CROW:
Walkie-talkie pickin' up, pal?
- Alright, Hank,
make your 180 degree turn.
JOEL:
Everybody lean.
- You take the one
on the right.
JOEL:
The big one?
CROW:
He's not my type.
TOM:
Oh! There's gunplay.
CROW:
I wanna hear a ricochet.
JOEL:
Why is it darker on the Earth
than on the Moon?
TOM:
A humanist question,
or a question
a human might ask?
JOEL:
They're at the Cadillac ranch.
CROW:
He's at a bang bang.
TOM:
What kind of a welcome party
is this?
CROW:
I hope this doesn't happen
at the hotel.
Did you call ahead?
Pa-too-ee.
- Let's get over to the car.
TOM:
Yeah, the bullets
don't hurt over there.
JOEL:
Get over here.
TOM:
Okay, sir.
Well, you'd notice
by all the [indistinct].
- They're taking off in a car.
I'll go after 'em,
you guard the ship.
JOEL:
I'll go after 'em
and leave you guys stranded.
CROW:
Thanks.
Let's hold each other.
- They're after us,
step on it.
CROW:
Hey, you almost lost him
in that last edit.
TOM:
Meanwhile,
hundreds of miles away...
CROW:
Good driving.
- He's hanging onto us.
Give it all you can.
TOM:
Nothing's worth
driving like that.
JOEL:
They don't even have
their belts on, I bet.
TOM:
Nice shot of me.
Whoa.
Another good shot of me.
I look like Gene Hackman.
- Stop on that bridge.
JOEL:
He's got an idea.
CROW:
Hey, wait. Didn't you see
the "bridge of death"
sign up there?
TOM:
Oh, litter. That'll do it.
Cody hates it when we litter.
JOEL:
Uh, you shouldn't drink
before you have a car chase.
TOM:
Let's put this garbage here,
Cody'll see it,
he'll stop, we'll get away.
We'd better go.
[ALL TALKING AT ONCE]
CROW:
I want to see how it ends.
JOEL:
Come on, let's go.
CROW:
I want to see this.
Oh, come on.
TOM:
Think Cody'll survive?
[HUMMING]
- Hey, whatta ya reading?
- Oh, it's the latest edition
of "Tiger Bot Magazine."
They have a big full color
spread of Data from Star Trek.
- Data, wow!
He's dreamy.
- Says here he's getting bigger
than Kirk Cameron too.
- Wow! Hey, hey,
look at that schematic there.
Wow, look at that brain.
- Wish I had me one of
those positronic brains.
- Wow, Data's got
all the candy.
Hey Servo, uh,
who's the dream date this week?
- Let me see...
says here...
Tweaky.
- Tweaky!
What a coaster.
He hasn't worked
since Buck Rogers.
- I know, what a putz.
Bidi-bidi-bidi,
wanna dance?
Buck.
[LAUGHS]
- Yeah.
You know, that guy
couldn't interface
without a load pan adapter.
Such a shrimpy
little bot anyway
with those ineffectual arms
and that stupid
bubble head, and...
- Funny, Crow.
- Whoops.
- Oh, great! Look,
here's the spreadsheets on Data.
Let's see, turn ons,
electricity,
quiet walks in the holodeck,
cray supercomputers.
Let's see, turn offs,
switches...
- Yeah.
- ...fat Klingons in sweatpants
and Shatner hanging around
the set telling old war stories.
Oh, here, and Tandy products.
Okay, pet peeves,
yes, definitely.
Favorite actress,
Julie Newmar.
Favorite Scotch,
James Doohan.
Secret fantasy--
hey, wait a minute,
look at this!
His secret fantasy
says right here,
"I'd really love to be a human."
Oh, man!
- Aw, how predictable.
The old Pinocchio syndrome.
- This is the kind of
clown that gives us bots
a really bad name.
- Yeah, what a sellout.
- And speaking of sellouts.
[♪♪♪]
TOM:
I just want to read
the article on Data.
JOEL:
I don't want you
reading this stuff.
TOM:
Hey, you're paying for that.
CROW:
Hey, litterbug, litterbug.
TOM:
[indistinct]
JOEL:
♪ A corpse is a horse ♪
♪ A corpse a corpse
Unless it... ♪
CROW:
It's The Little Rascals
music again.
JOEL:
Yeah.
Hey, look at the shadow
I cast, you guys.
CROW:
Wow.
TOM:
I think you're
casting credits, too.
CROW:
Hey, do the rabbit.
JOEL:
Naw, I can't do that.
CROW:
Eh, looked more like
Abe Lincoln.
TOM:
Or Abe Vigoda really.
Wallace Fox,
I'd like to hunt him down
and skin him
and make him into a little rug.
JOEL:
I'll get it.
CROW:
Hey, why is the groom
looking at us?
TOM:
He's never been
in a movie before.
JOEL:
Hey Doc,
he's gonna see us.
- ...lawfully wedded husband,
to love, honor and obey,
until death do you part?
- I-- I do.
[CRIES OUT]
CROW:
Nice die.
TOM:
You may now bury the bride.
- Take her into the anteroom.
- Yes, sir.
CROW: And keep it quiet.
People want
to take their gifts back
if they hear about this.
[CHATTERING]
JOEL:
It ruins so many wedding nights
when the bride dies.
- Please,
this is no time for interviews.
- Shall I telephone
for the ambulance?
- No, the undertaker.
She's dead.
CROW:
Whoa, must be the father
of the bride, Gloomy Gus.
TOM:
Sensitive guy.
JOEL:
Oh man, that's so sad.
Look, they're taking
the cake back.
TOM:
Thank you, I love cake.
Ooo, the frosting
is delicious!
Alright, we got the cake,
now step on it.
CROW:
Step on the cake, ew.
TOM:
No, the car-- you!
JOEL:
Bing.
- Hey, all of you can go now.
TOM:
Wow, life savers, thanks.
- Gee, thanks.
JOEL:
Lucky guy.
CROW:
Hey, the red ones are missing.
- Good evening, Dr. Rayburn.
I'm from the Forest Mortuary.
- Forest Mortuary?
But two of your men
just drove away
with the body
a few moments ago.
TOM: Huh?
- There must be some mistake.
They weren't our men.
- Well, I've heard of
ambulance chasing
but this is something new.
- New? It's sensational.
Another kidnapping
of a dead bride, what a story!
JOEL:
What a sensitive pair.
CROW:
Yeah.
TOM:
Body of dead bride disappears.
Audience baffled
by free floating headlines.
Trite headline device
used to enhance plot.
Producers hope to work
in calendar flipping
before the end of the film.
- And a few minutes ago,
one of the men
who helped remove
the body of the...
TOM:
Equally trite
radio announcer device.
- ...was apprehended
by the police.
- Go on. Keep talking.
- But I told you I was standing
on the corner
minding my own business
when along comes
the stiff wagon.
A guy pokes his head
out of the window
and asked me if I wanted
to make a couple of bucks.
CROW:
And some Lifesavers.
- Two. At least
all I could see.
- What'd they look like?
- I don't know.
It was dark.
I didn't pay no attention
to faces.
- You notice the license?
- What with two bucks
staring me in the face?
- Come on, tell the truth.
What'd you do with the corpse?
- I didn't do nothing with it.
JOEL:
He's gonna need that two bucks
to buy a new hat.
CROW:
Yeah.
TOM:
Shadowy corpse thief escapes.
Trite headline device
still ineffective.
Building still large.
- As District Attorney,
Mrs. Wentworth,
I assure you
there won't be any trouble.
You can proceed
with the wedding as planned.
- Well, we want some
assurance besides words.
We want protection.
JOEL:
Aw, you shoulda discussed that
with your daughter
earlier.
- And if I'm any judge of
the appearance of your daughter,
she looks as healthy
as she is beautiful.
- Oh really, mother.
I think you're making
much ado about nothing.
CROW:
Hey, I thought
Shakespeare wrote that.
- Not in the least.
- Well, if we have protection,
I'll feel
much better about it.
- You'll have it alright,
Mrs. Wentworth.
JOEL:
Boy, what a couple
of ugly hats,
call the fashion police.
- ...wait, I'll pick him up.
- That's the Wentworth
mother and daughter, isn't it?
Is the wedding called off?
- Certainly not.
And there isn't gonna be
any trouble either.
- That's what
all the rest of them thought.
- I can't answer for
Miss Wentworth's health
but your paper
can print one thing,
and that is that there'll be
no more theft of girls' bodies.
CROW [WOMAN'S VOICE]:
Well, we shall see.
- Yeah, this will get you
and Sandy into the wedding
and I want plenty
of photographs.
- Ho ho, don't worry, boss.
I got enough film
to cover the Russian front.
TOM:
But he'll get chocolate
on the pictures.
- ...to take me
off the society column.
- Oh, quit beefing.
You're getting a break.
This is the most exclusive
wedding of the year.
- What if the Wentworth girl
drops dead too?
- You'll still tell me
what she's wearing
along with the rest
of the fancy pants.
JOEL:
That's cold.
- Get me the guest list
and don't bother
about anything else.
JOEL: Let me get that for you.
- ...with the police,
and they'll be plenty more
thereabouts.
And if the bride
holds up this time,
there won't be any snatching.
Now get going.
- What if I get a clue.
- Oh, I wouldn't let
that bother me, sweetie pie.
You wouldn't know a clue
if it bit you!
- I'll remember
those words, stooge.
CROW: [MAKES SOUNDS LIKE
THE THREE STOOGES CURLY]
♪ I'm getting buried
In the morning ♪
♪ Buried dead
Getting buried... ♪
JOEL: Good one.
- ...nervous mother.
After all, I'm the one
that's getting married.
- Oh, I just can't help it.
I'm so afraid
something will go wrong.
- Oh, forget it.
Nothing can possibly happen.
TOM:
Shhh, donk. Dadadada...
- Oh, Allen!
It's perfect...
JOEL:
Oh hi.
You're gonna make
a perfect dead bride...
TOM:
Keep a section of the dress.
You'll need them
for your toes.
JOEL:
Same fabric in the coffin.
I get your car for you, sir?
- ...and this wedding
won't wait for us.
- Can I help it
if we had a blowout?
- Serves you right.
Why don't you buy
some new tires for this bug?
- You know, I've been
thinking of getting--
hey, are you kidding?
ALL:
Oh! Doh!
JOEL:
I can't believe he went
for that blowout story.
He really is a stooge.
[CROW IMITATES CURLY]
TOM:
Keep your space cushion,
check your blind spot, hands
at ten and two on the wheel.
CROW:
Five minutes, Mr. Lugosi.
JOEL [IMITATES BELA LUGOSI]:
I'm going to jump
out of this truck
and scare the pants
off everybody.
Blah! Blah!
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
CROW:
Land shark.
It's Nelson Eddy.
- You mustn't come in here.
It's bad luck!
- Aw, not even a peak?
- Not even one.
You'll see me soon enough.
- You see?
TOM: Oh.
CROW: Simp.
- Oh girls, do you mind
if I have these last few minutes
alone with Alice?
[ALL GIRLS TALKING TOGETHER]
[ALL COMMENTATORS
IMITATING GIRLS]
JOEL:
...she's gonna die anyway.
- Well, mother,
you're about to lose me.
- I hope not forever, dear.
- 'Course not.
What are you talking about?
- Do you feel all right, dear?
- Certainly. I never
felt better in my life.
You should forget
all that silly nonsense
about those brides
dropping dead.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
JOEL:
Telegram.
- For Miss Wentworth.
- Oh, thank you.
CROW:
Seems like
a nice enough fella...
ALL:
...at first!
- From Dwight.
- No doubt.
TOM:
It's a box lunch.
I love corn beef.
- Wear this next to
your heart, darling.
All my love.
[SIGHS]
What an unusual orchid.
CROW: That's the package.
- ...saw one like it before.
It's lovely.
- It's beautiful!
ALL:
It's deadly!
JOEL [IMITATES LUGOSI]:
Now for my famous
metamorphosis illusion.
I entered the back
of the hearse,
no one's looking, and...
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
CROW:
Pizza delivery.
- The minister is ready,
Mrs. Wentworth.
- Thank you.
CROW: Get out of here.
- Say a little prayer, darling.
JOEL: I'll readjust that.
CROW: Muzza wuzzawuzza.
Fuzza wuzzawuzza.
How's that?
JOEL:
Mmm, coulda been longer.
Do you promise to love,
cherish, obey,
until death do you... huh?
[CRIES OUT]
CROW:
Nice die.
- Alice, Alice, Alice!
Oh, darling,
darling, are you alright?
[ALL COMMENTATORS MUMBLING]
- It happened again.
- I just got the picture
of the month.
TOM:
For dead bride magazine.
JOEL:
Oh man, they're taking
the deli tray away?
I think that's so scary.
CROW:
Yeah, but we can sell it
to the Feinberg wedding.
JOEL:
Speaking of selling...
[♪♪♪]
JOEL:
Paunch, John, follow 'em.
TOM [IMITATES LUGOSI]:
Peak-a-boo, my little lamb chop.
CROW:
What a bonehead.
JOEL:
Can I get your door for you?
- I just told the news
to Keenan,
did you get anymore pictures?
- Did I get pictures?
I covered everything except
a close-up of this pretty posy.
- Why, that looks like
the one the bride wore.
What are you doing with it?
- Presenting it
to you, sweetheart,
as a token of my devotion.
Take a smell.
- Who ever heard of
an orchid with a scent?
- Well, that one has.
Maybe it's a clue.
- What a peculiar sweet odor.
JOEL:
Oh, that's me.
- Yeah, make a swell
romaine salad.
JOEL:
What a strange sense of flavor.
- Hey, Pat?
You're not gonna
pass out too, are you?
- No, no, I'm okay.
TOM:
It's just the pace of this movie
that's got to me.
JOEL: Need a push?
TOM: Okay.
That's nutty.
CROW:
Hey! It's a hotrod.
- You stay right here.
JOEL:
I gotta scare 'em away.
CROW:
Good heater.
JOEL:
You know, that wouldn't happen
if he had thrush pipes on it,
I'm sure of it.
[IMITATES LUGOSI]
Peak-a-boo, I see you.
Are you frightened yet?
Grab the spare tire,
the toolbox, and the deli tray.
Then we short-sheet the bed!
I love these frat pranks.
TOM:
Oh, so that's how they do
the vanishing corpse trick.
There's a secret panel
in the back
and they take it out.
I feel like I've been taken.
- What kind of a gag is this?
No driver, no license plate.
- Maybe it isn't a gag,
maybe it's a decoy.
ALL:
Nah!
CROW:
Yeah, but don't bother
putting it out.
TOM: Wuh-oh.
JOEL: What's going on here?
Check it out.
TOM:
Two abandoned hearses
in one day?
What are the odds
of that happening?
- Calling all cars.
Calling all cars.
Another abduction
of a girl's corpse.
Brunette,
22 years of age,
stop and search all trucks
and suspicious looking cars.
CROW:
Be on the lookout
for my toupee.
- That's all.
Burnside.
- Carlo?
We're taking a look
inside this rig.
- Sure thing, officer.
JOEL:
But I don't have
any dead bodies in back
or anything if that's what
you're talking about.
I don't mind showing you.
Come around to the back here,
nothing wrong here.
Check it out.
TOM:
What's that then?
Hey, I'm in here!
JOEL:
Hey, they should check
underneath them.
CROW:
Looks like
a driver's license photo.
- Alright, go ahead.
- Change that headline to read,
"Is Wedlock Challenged?"
Then set up an editorial
attacking the DEA's office
for playing marbles
while some madman runs away
with the bodies
of dead brides.
[JOEL'S MUFFLED SPEECH]
- Send up the proofs
right away.
CROW:
And get me a ham on rye.
- So, it's you.
Well,
of all the rotten stories
that have ever been turned
into this office,
yours takes the prize.
No guest list,
and we don't even know
what the bride wore.
- She wore this orchid.
- Listen, Miss Hunter,
I have a great responsibility.
I'm a public servant.
Parents are calling in
The Chronicle frantically
with tears in their voice,
begging for news
of their daughters.
I have a daughter myself
who's about to be married.
Maybe she'll drop dead too.
But she won't drop dead
from an orchid.
- I didn't say that.
- Well, then
what are you talking about?
- Every one of the brides
that died and disappeared
were wearing
one of these orchids.
- How do you know?
- Well, I checked.
TOM: It's my job.
- Look at these pictures.
- Alright, perhaps
it's a coincidence.
It still doesn't
spell anything.
- Then where did the
Wentworth girl get this orchid?
The bridegroom
didn't give it to her.
JOEL:
Huh?
- ...a dozen people
gave it to her.
Her mammy, her pappy.
JOEL:
The guy she went out with.
- Besides, this orchid
has peculiar odor.
That's unusual.
JOEL: That's me.
- ...why don't you follow it up?
- Is that an assignment?
- It's a notice
that you're through
if you don't
bring something in.
- Okay, Mr. Keenan.
TOM:
Meanwhile,
back at the Adams Family home...
CROW:
Oh, that must be Stanley,
their garage door opener.
Always trying to help
people do things right.
[GIGGLE]
Everything... uh, ow.
JOEL:
Bring it in.
Hey, there's Billy Barty
and Cloris Leachman.
TOM:
What's with the noise?
You trying to wake the dead?
CROW:
He doesn't have any pants on
underneath that thing.
TOM:
I'm glad it's shut then.
JOEL:
It's a soapbox racer.
CROW:
Don't open it.
- My little family.
You're also very fateful.
- Master,
the Countess is waiting.
- Upstairs?
- There.
- Oh, we must hurry.
Mike?
JOEL:
That's one scary name, Mike.
CROW:
Mike.
JOEL:
The evil henchman, Mike.
TOM:
Sends shivers up my diode.
CROW:
Well, here comes
Meals On Wheels.
JOEL:
Let me help you
with that there, mmm-hmm.
CROW:
Oh Mike, posture, posture.
TOM:
He has stone walls
painted on his drywall.
[MOANING]
CROW:
She's practicing for
her role as Camille.
- Are you suffering,
my beloved.
- Terribly!
You must hurry.
[MOANS]
- I'm so sorry.
But I was detained.
Please forgive me.
- Forgive you?
You loiter and waste time,
while I wait here dying.
Dying!
TOM:
Well, it'd make
for a shorter movie.
- I will not let you die.
- Better death
than agony like this.
JOEL:
No wonder
it's taking them so long,
look how long
it takes them to dress.
- Look at me, look at me!
CROW:
Uh, no thanks. I just ate.
- Now, will you hurry?
JOEL:
See, he's still not done
bundling up.
TOM:
Why is he putting on gloves?
She's dead.
What's the point?
JOEL:
Maybe
he's a performance artist.
We don't know.
CROW:
Hey, do you think
he's a real doctor?
I don't see
no diplomas on his wall.
TOM:
I think he went to Scare U.
[MOANING]
Free ear piercing with death.
CROW:
He's doing the ear piercing
with a conductor's punch,
though.
TOM:
Yee.
JOEL [IMITATES BUGOSI]:
Yes.
That felt good.
Ah.
CROW:
All that just for
a little maple syrup.
JOEL:
Now we can have
the rich taste of bride
any time we want it.
CROW:
You know, it's not just
for breakfast anymore.
JOEL:
Right.
[GROANING]
TOM:
He never calls anymore.
He just comes over
and shoots me with big needles.
CROW:
She's a quart low.
[GROANING]
- Courage, my dear.
Courage.
[GROANING]
TOM:
Don't throw the cotton ball.
CROW:
Now you might feel
a little sting.
[SCREAMS]
Okay, a big sting.
JOEL:
Lovely... lovely.
[GASPING]
JOEL:
Lovely... lovely.
TOM: [SINGING TO THE TUNE
OF "WHIP IT" BY DEVO]
♪ When a hunchback
Comes along... ♪
JOEL:
♪ You must whip him ♪
TOM:
♪ He's playing with your
Corpse... ♪
JOEL:
♪ Unless you whip him ♪
TOM:
♪ He will not go away... ♪
JOEL:
♪ You must whip him ♪
TOM:
♪ Whip him whip your hunchback ♪
CROW:
Well,
that'll straighten him out.
- Why do you beat
my son so hard.
- Because he's a beast,
an animal.
And someday I should
like to destroy him.
TOM: It's just a hunch.
JOEL: [LAUGHS] Good one.
- My poor son.
Why was he ever born?
CROW:
'Cause you didn't play safely.
- Can you bear
to look at me now?
CROW:
He can even look at you bare.
- You're beautiful.
And I shall always
keep you that way.
TOM:
Hasn't he heard of cryogenics?
CROW:
Or saran wrap.
JOEL:
Or Tupperware?
- Does she live?
- As long as
she can be of any use to us.
- She's pretty.
- Mmm.
- Very young.
- All of them must be.
Come, my dear.
JOEL:
Let's get out of here too.
TOM:
What did they call her?
[♪♪♪]
[GASPING]
- Oh, man!
[MOANING]
[PANTING]
- Whoa, no!
- Oooooo.
Tag, you're it.
- Hey, wait wait.
Wait, wait, wait.
Come here,
come here, you guys.
Come on back here.
- What do you want?
- What's going on?
- Face, tag! You're it!
[ALARM BUZZING]
- Oh you!
- Movie sign!
- None of the florists
I checked with
ever saw an orchid like that.
- Well, that's not surprising.
This particular...
JOEL:
I tricked you guys.
TOM:
You really skunked us.
CROW:
You cheated.
TOM:
Next time we play TV tag.
- No.
But if you wish to
find out more about it...
JOEL:
Read about it at your library.
- ...name of Lorenz.
He was the one who originally
hybridized this plant,
over in Europe somewhere.
- But I just can't go to Europe,
just to...
- That isn't necessary.
He lives up at Brookdale now.
TOM:
Oh, how convenient.
- Thank you, Mr. Smith.
- You're quite welcome.
JOEL:
He lives at a mall?
[BELL RINGING]
- Looks like that box
got a coffin in it, Jack.
- Sure it does.
JOEL: A box full of box.
- What do you suppose
he wants with a coffin?
- Search me.
He's such a strange,
spooky guy.
The further I stay
away from him, the better.
- Me too.
CROW:
What a goofball.
- I'll take charge of this.
- Go ahead.
Take it away.
Glad to get rid of it.
JOEL:
Something stupid
this way comes.
- Taxi, lady?
CROW:
No, it's a suitcase.
- Right this way.
Where to, Miss?
- To the home
of Professor Lorenz.
- Lorenz? I'm sorry,
I can't take you there.
I'm outta gas.
- You mean,
you won't take me?
TOM:
Usually the "out of gas" thing
comes later
in the relationship.
- Is this the only taxi in town?
- Yes, ma'am, it is.
- Look, I've simply got to
get to the Lorenz place.
I'll make...
JOEL: Listen, dope.
You take her with you.
- That truck's going up there.
You might get a ride with him.
That is, if you don't mind
riding with a coffin.
CROW:
Are you kidding? I love coffins.
Point me at it.
- Would you give me a lift
to the Lorenz place?
- What do you want to
go there for?
- To see the professor.
- Does he expect you?
- No, but I...
- Then we can't take you.
TOM:
Jeez, welcome to Snotty-dale.
JOEL:
She's determined
to get on that truck.
TOM:
Oh, I love those skirts.
Really attractive.
CROW:
♪ I'm a little teacup
Short and... ♪
Hey! Boss, the plane,
the plane!
I mean, uh,
the babe, the babe.
JOEL:
I think you have to be
under 43 inches
to ride on that ride.
- Get off and stay off!
- Look, I've got to see
Professor Lorenz,
it's important.
- I said you couldn't ride.
CROW:
But she's got a ticket
to ride.
TOM:
She don't care.
JOEL:
It's an eTicket though,
and you know how short
those eTicket rides are.
- ...you got my bag!
Oh.
TOM:
Doh.
And then frustration set in.
JOEL:
Sheesh.
TOM:
She looks as fresh
as a country lane
after a fresh spring shower.
- Would you mind
giving me a lift?
- Certainly not.
Where are you going?
- I'm trying to get to
the home of Professor Lorenz.
- Well, you're in luck.
That's where I'm going.
JOEL:
Hey, so are we!
TOM:
Yeah, yeah.
Professor Lorenz, yeah,
come in, yeah, yeah.
CROW:
Great.
- My name is Dr. Foster.
- I'm Patricia Hunter.
JOEL: I'm Joel.
TOM: I'm Servo.
CROW: And I'm Crow.
- No, I'm a reporter.
TOM: I'm a robot.
JOEL: I'm a human being.
- You're his doctor, I presume?
- Not exactly.
Lorenz is a doctor himself
but he has no license
to practice.
JOEL: Making him a quack.
- ...working with him.
We're trying to find
a cure for his wife.
- Oh, I see.
What type of people
are the Lorenzs?
JOEL: Human.
- ...find them very interesting.
Professor Lorenz is a man
of unusual accomplishment.
But his wife
is rather peculiar.
I expect you'll find them both
a bit eccentric.
JOEL:
I like that.
Eccentric.
Think we'll see Stanley?
TOM:
No, I think-- no.
It's Janie,
the garage door opener.
[JOEL LAUGHS]
CROW:
He hates those jokes.
TOM:
He started it.
CROW:
He was frightened
by a garage door
as a child.
JOEL:
You know, he used to play
at the Ice Capades.
CROW:
Why, nobody eats the--
oh, I didn't see it
down there.
- Toby,
tell your master I'm here.
TOM:
May I take your skirt?
JOEL:
Is it just me,
or is he really small?
CROW:
It's called foreshortening.
- ...isn't he?
- I told you
they were eccentric.
- I'm inclined
to believe you.
TOM:
Excuse me.
Hey, you up there.
You, up there!
- Get out, you gargoyle.
Get out!
CROW:
You're no prize yourself, babe.
- Good evening, Dr. Foster.
Come right in.
- Good evening,
Professor Lorenz, Countess.
May I present
Miss Patricia Hunter.
- How do you do.
- We have been expecting you.
- So, you found my bag
in your truck.
- Yes. There it is.
- Miss Hunter's
a newspaper woman, and...
- I came here hoping you might
grant me an interview.
- An interview?
About what?
- No one asked you
to come here.
You are not welcome!
ALL:
Nice tag!
- ...my dear.
I'm sure Miss Hunter
meant no harm.
Please forgive my wife,
she's not well.
Come, you'd better retire.
CROW:
Good punch for a southpaw.
- So, that's what you call
being eccentric.
Well, I have
another name for it.
CROW:
I call it "bitchy."
- I do not like that girl.
She's here for no good.
- We have nothing to fear.
JOEL:
But fear itself.
TOM:
♪ The weather started
Getting rough ♪
- I'm sorry, Professor,
if we're intruding.
- Not at all, Dr. Foster.
This is our evening for work.
Please, be seated.
- Thank you.
TOM:
My wife tends to
slap everybody.
- What do you wish
to interview me about.
- Orchids.
- Orchids?
- Yes, I understand
that you're an authority
on the subject.
- They were once my hobby,
but I haven't grown any
for several years.
Which species
are you interested in?
- A very rare one,
of the Stanhope type.
A horticulturist told me
that you're the original
hybridizer of it.
CROW:
Nobody calls me that and lives.
- Yes, I have one in my bag.
I'll show it to you.
TOM:
I got it off a dead bride.
- Where did you get it?
- Oh, um...
a friend of mine
gave it to me.
You see, I'm doing an article
on orchids for my newspaper,
and I thought that you'd be
willing to supply me
with some special data.
- I'm sorry, I can't spare
the time tonight, Miss Hunter.
You see, I have very important
work to do with Dr. Foster.
CROW: The real doctor.
- I understand.
- If your interview
can wait until morning,
I'll drive you
back here then.
If that's agreeable
with Professor Lorenz.
- It's quite agreeable
but I would suggest
that you both stay here
as my guests.
- Thank you very much,
but I prefer going to a hotel.
- Just as you wish.
CROW:
Why, I happen to have a hotel
right behind this curtain.
- I think it would be foolish
to go out in such storm.
- The professor is right,
Miss Hunter.
Perhaps we had better remain.
However, if you insist,
I'll gladly drive you back
to the village.
- I'm afraid that would be
an imposition
since you've
so much work to do.
TOM: Yes, it would.
- Thank you, I'll stay.
JOEL:
But I don't like it.
- Toby will show you
to your rooms.
TOM:
You'll be sleeping
with the monkey-boy tonight.
- Toby, take up
Miss Hunter's bags.
JOEL:
He's a bellboy too.
- Goodnight.
- Goodnight, I'll meet you
in the study soon.
- Very well.
CROW:
These kooks are
coming out of the woodwork.
- Why did you ask her
to spend the night here?
JOEL [IMITATES LUGOSI]:
She's got legs
and she knows
how to use them.
- Very special reason.
TOM:
He's been injecting her
with young and pretty,
now he should start injecting
her with smart and nice.
- Thank you.
JOEL: Is it appropriate to tip?
CROW:
Long as you write him again.
TOM:
Think if you tipped him,
he'd fall right over.
- I guess you
sleep very good, maybe.
[SINISTER LAUGH]
JOEL: [CHUCKLES]
He thinks that's funny?
- Few times I've stayed
overnight here,
I've slept unusually well.
- Must be wonderful
to have nerves like that.
Tell me, just how well
do you know these people.
- Why actually,
not very well.
I've only recently moved
into the village.
You know, a young doctor
trying to
establish a practice.
CROW:
And a mustache.
- Well, I must be
keeping you from your work.
Goodnight, doctor.
- Goodnight.
TOM:
Oops, wrong scene.
JOEL:
I think she's looking
for the other two
Andrew Sisters.
CROW:
Patty and Maxene?
- What do you want?
- Yes, you are beautiful.
- How did you get in here?
- So young.
Such lovely skin.
TOM:
You'd look good
rotating on the spit.
- Sometime you too
will be a bride.
CROW:
Fresh.
Hey,
I was gonna make espresso.
Where'd you go?
TOM:
People rarely walk out
on international coffees.
JOEL:
He's taken all her toiletries.
Oh, that little guy,
he probably just wants
some attention.
He really likes her so...
Maybe he's out in the yard
playing on a swing set.
I can't confront him, though.
Yes, yes,
let it be known I love him.
Doc, Dopey, Sneezy.
TOM:
This is much better
than my own passage
through the sock drawer.
CROW:
While the reporter sleeps,
a pasty film covers her mouth.
JOEL [IMITATES LUGOSI]:
I just love to watch her sleep.
Look at how pretty
her hair looks.
Her pajamas are darling.
Sure, I love my wife,
but the upkeep on her
is unbelievable.
It's outrageous,
seven corpses a week.
If only she could cut back.
Now I'll walk backwards.
Yes.
TOM:
I've gotta go back here
and talk to the lion
and the witch.
CROW:
She awakes with the worst
breath of the day.
JOEL:
But it's his breath.
CROW:
Ew.
TOM:
Maybe I was just
imagining things.
[♪♪♪]
TOM:
Meanwhile,
back at the mutant heap,
Stanley gets ready
for another grueling day
at the asbestos factory.
- I know where you're going.
[GROANS]
CROW:
Hey, don't be short with me.
- Some day,
the master will catch you.
[GROANS]
- Then you'll be sorry.
TOM:
What's he gonna do,
straighten his spine out?
JOEL:
Boy, somebody sure woke up
on the wrong side
of the slab this morning.
Dig my shadow?
[TOM GIGGLES]
JOEL [IMITATES LUGOSI]:
No, this man
is a different story.
No, his hair is all wrong.
Maybe I get rid
of the mustache definitely.
It's a crime to hide
those classic features.
He sleeps so peacefully.
It's a shame to hide him.
I must walk backwards.
TOM:
Night of the Living Shadows.
CROW:
Hey, I brought you
some cheese bread
and a little glass of milk.
JOEL:
Now, if I had my way,
I'd do her hair
completely differently.
I'd toss her hair back
and rope it off
with a little chaparral.
It'd be just so lovely.
See, she's lost
a lot of protein,
I'd give her
a kind of a protein wash
and then a rinse
and then maybe we'd...
[SCREAMS]
CROW:
I don't think she wants a wash.
TOM:
Make sure you get
all those clothes on.
Yeah, get everything.
Get the shoes,
the housecoat...
CROW:
You might say that she's
dressing for distress.
TOM:
Smartly done,
but she just does not know
how to accessorize.
- Dr. Foster?
Dr. Foster?
CROW:
Dr. Denton?
- Dr. Foster?
Dr. Foster?
TOM:
Dr. Scholls? Dr. Pepper?
CROW:
Kinky.
JOEL:
Oh, they look so good.
So peaceful.
They never looked that good.
- Dr. Foster.
- What's wrong?
- I just saw someone
in my room.
A horrible looking creature.
CROW:
Aw, that's just Stanley,
the gnarled but lovable
garage door opener.
- He disappeared back there.
JOEL:
Oh, you've got some
nice outfits in here.
Love that Teddy.
CROW: Teddy bear?
- Well, he's not here now.
Where did you see him?
- Leaning over my bed.
- 'Course, you might
have been dreaming.
- I'm positive I wasn't.
Earlier in the evening,
Mrs. Lorenz suddenly appeared
and then disappeared.
Do you suppose there's
another entrance to this room?
- Oh, I doubt it.
Why don't you try
to go back to sleep.
No one's going to harm you.
I'm sure it was just
a nightmare.
- I think this whole place
is a nightmare.
ALL:
So do we.
- ...his wife were actually
sleeping in coffins.
I saw them.
- We often find it difficult
to explain the peculiarities
of some people.
CROW:
They're foreign, you know.
- I'm awfully sorry
to bother you.
- There's no trouble.
If you're frightened,
call me again.
- Goodnight.
TOM:
Goodnight.
CROW:
What a fright-light.
- What is the trouble?
JOEL [IMITATES LUGOSI]:
Nothing dear, go back to bed.
- He has disturbed our guests.
- [indistinct]
He is a menace to us.
- Yes.
CROW:
But he's good with the kids.
- It seems the time has come
to dispose of him.
TOM:
Disposable hunchbacks?
JOEL:
This closet is huge.
I could fit a ton
of new outfits in here.
TOM:
It's a drive in closet.
CROW:
Her jammies are really slinky.
TOM:
Silky to a fault.
CROW:
I've got a bad feeling
about this.
Joel, I gotta sense
there's a long
basement scene coming up.
TOM:
Even got its own
annoying music.
JOEL:
A love theme to the basement.
TOM:
The chilling love theme
from The Corpse Vanishes.
Billions sold in Europe.
CROW:
There's the cast
of Carnival Story.
TOM:
Little leg of the dog
that bit him.
[CROW HUMMING WITH SOUNDTRACK]
Gotta get that on tape.
Hey, lady, slow down.
Hey, art exhibit my nose.
Hey, come back here.
Hey, lady.
JOEL:
Character actor,
Burgess Meredith.
CROW:
Hey, posture.
TOM:
I guess Stanley didn't see
the "no diving" sign that day.
CROW:
His eating habits
are atrocious.
Hey, that's what I'm on about,
litter bug!
JOEL:
Let this be a lesson
to you guys.
Always lift with your knees,
or your gonna end up
like Stanley did.
TOM:
We don't have knees, Joel.
CROW:
Is this a walk on role for him?
TOM:
No, it's a walk on, and on,
and on role.
CROW:
Well, no one can hold a candle
to his performance.
JOEL:
I think they could,
but no one
would really want to.
CROW:
Maybe they could douse him
with something flammable
and then hold a candle to him.
Saved a lot of money
on the lighting in this.
JOEL:
Stanley's having
some midnight delight.
TOM:
It's a seven corpse meal.
CROW:
Oh!
[TOM LAUGHS]
JOEL:
Now, I would do something
completely different.
You see, teasing the hair
takes protein out.
Using protein 21 religiously
helps put back
some of the protein
that shampooing takes out.
It's one heck of a shampoo.
TOM: Joel?
JOEL: Yeah?
TOM: That's really irritating.
JOEL: Okay. Sorry.
TOM:
Stop it.
JOEL:
Pretty.
[CLATTERING SOUND]
- Uh?
JOEL: Hmm?
TOM:
These brides are
really piling up in here.
CROW:
Stop slouching.
Or slumming,
as the case may be.
[CROW SCREECHING
TO TUNE OF SOUNDTRACK]
[TOM JOINS CROW]
JOEL:
Uh-oh.
[GROANS]
- Don't be afraid, Angel.
I would not hurt you.
[GROANS]
CROW:
No, he doesn't want to
hurt him.
It's just high impact
chiropractics.
JOEL [IMITATES LUGOSI]:
That felt great.
Now I clean up
with a little lava.
CROW:
Real lava.
TOM: Here we go, Joel.
JOEL: Nope.
CROW:
Oh...
TOM:
Carry me back
to the old satellite.
CROW: Carry me too.
JOEL: Nope, I can't carry you.
You've got wheels.
CROW: Oh, come on, carry me.
TOM:
You have legs.
[WHISTLING]
- Well, so.
What can I do
for you today, big boy?
- Just, uh,
give me the usual.
- All right,
you want the ears left on?
[CHUCKLES]
- Right.
- Eh,
little barber joke there.
Well, okay.
Now-- oh say!
Did you hear
about the Mason boy?
- Uh, Jimmy, the oldest?
- Yup.
Got uh, got caught
in the family thresher machine.
- Oh no.
[WHISTLING]
- Dad had to pull him out
with the come along.
- Yeah, well the good news is
now he gets to play center
over at the new high school.
Turn please.
- On the basketball team?
[WHISTLING]
- Looks like the Dixons are
marrying off their youngest.
- Oh, Pixie.
She's a super gal.
- Oh yeah.
- Yeah, I remember her when
she was just a little darling.
You know, she's marrying
the Fenton boy now.
He's trouble.
Lean left.
No, your other left.
[CHUCKLES]
Yeah, he's taking hydraulics
over at the Vo-Tech.
- Didn't that refrigeration
course pan out for him?
- Well, it did until
the Freon accident.
JOEL AND TOM:
Oh no.
- Mmm. Yup, yup.
Eh-uh, whatta ya want me
to do with this cyst?
- Oh, just comb over it, okay?
You know,
I saw the Fentons go over
to the hot fish shop,
you know?
- Oh.
Oh, they do a nice job
over there.
Oh, the relish tray
to die for.
We gotta bring
the girls down there.
They just love it.
- Yeah, they love that place.
- Was that your ear?
- No.
- How about that?
- Ouch!
[LAUGHING]
- There goes your tip.
- Yup.
Well, hey, you know, I was,
I was up the Crazy Days
over at Baskerville,
you know, the other day
for that clown parade
thing they do, Joel.
Yeah, you heard of that.
Yeah, sure.
They get the Lions Club
together
with the Kiwanis
from Ellsworth,
there's about
150 of them there
for this clown jamboree,
you know?
And well, you know,
about 150 clowns running wild
in the street
with the big clown suits
and the fake mustard
and all that stuff.
- Yeah,
they do a wonderful job.
- Oh, yeah.
Well, I know how much you boys
like clowns, you know,
and well,
these boys, anyway,
they took a few tall cold ones
and that wasn't even enough.
They had a few
road sodas with him,
you know what I mean?
And well, they ended up
rolling that fire engine
right there
in the main street.
Gasoline and clown white
all over the road.
- Oh.
- Yup.
And you know, those clown shoes
burn like black tires.
Yup. Big black stinky cloud
hanging over
the whole ugly scene.
Why, they're still
picking up clown noses.
- Wow.
- Oh.
- Yup. And they called
the coroner from up at Bixby.
You know,
he's got that ambulance
from the war, you know.
He's the only one in town.
And they still managed to
cram all 200 of them clowns
into that little, bitty wagon.
- That's um...
- Yup.
Sad thing.
[♪♪♪]
JOEL:
I think it's a pretty good
haircut.
TOM:
I think your head looks
like it was chewed on
by a rat, Joel.
- Morning, Miss Hunter.
- Good morning...
CROW:
Well, that's where
I got the idea.
- Oh, I'm sorry,
I thought you were up.
- Up? I've been up all night
with dead people.
- Dead people?
What do you mean?
- Come in,
and I'll tell you.
TOM:
Not much of a party.
- What kind of a place is this?
Last night I had the most
horrible experience of my life.
- Well, what was it?
- I saw lots of girls
in crypts
down underneath this house.
CROW:
Oh, don't knock
or anything, Bela.
- What was that you were saying,
Miss Hunter?
- Why have you a mausoleum
in the basement?
- Mausoleum?
What the hell
are you talking about?
- You know
what I'm talking about...
TOM:
Can the balloon juice, Prof.
I know what I'm talking about.
- ...creature.
- My dear,
you must've had a bad dream.
- Now look, Professor.
This was no dream.
TOM:
This was no boating accident.
- Shortly after
I called you and told you
about that horrible creature
in my room.
- Is that true, Dr. Foster?
- Well, I don't recall anything
about it, Miss Hunter.
You must be mistaken.
- Well, if I was dreaming,
it was the darndest
nightmare I ever had.
- Well, I slept
very soundly myself.
- Miss Hunter was rather upset,
I think, when she retired.
You see now, in dreams,
our minds play strange tricks
on us sometimes.
JOEL:
Yeah, like the little wiener
between the fingers trick.
- Oh, Professor?
That orchid I brought up here
to show you is gone.
I couldn't find it in my bag.
- That's too bad.
Perhaps you forgot to pack it.
Will you be down soon?
- Yes, right away.
- Are you coming, Doctor?
- Of course.
CROW:
Joel, why don't you wear
nice things like that.
JOEL:
Well, I got shot into space.
There wasn't any time to pack.
CROW:
Oh.
What's wrong with her?
TOM:
She's in love
with the hunchback.
Can't eat, can't sleep,
all she wants to do
is be with him.
Be with him!
- Shall we go into breakfast?
- No thank you.
I've got to get back
to the city.
Will you drive me
to the station, Dr. Foster?
- I'll be glad to.
- But what about the interview?
- Well, that'll have to wait
until some other time.
I just remembered
an appointment at the office,
so I've got to catch
the next train.
If you'll excuse me, Countess?
- Yes, I will excuse you.
JOEL:
And then I'll slap you.
- Professor, do you also make
a hobby of collecting coffins?
- Why yes,
in a manner of speaking.
I find a coffin much more
comfortable than a bed.
CROW [IMITATES LUGOSI]:
It's a water coffin.
- Many people do so, my dear.
Is it so strange
that I accept one
while waiting
for eternal rest?
- No, I suppose not.
Well, thank you
for your hospitality.
Goodbye.
TOM:
Wait, it is strange.
- I trust
we will meet again.
It has been so nice
meeting you.
JOEL:
What a sweet couple.
CROW:
Kooky.
- Don't tell me
I'm still dreaming.
- Well, what do you mean?
- That gravedigger,
he's real, isn't he?
JOEL:
What gravedigger?
- Oh, he's real alright.
But I hardly think
he's a gravedigger.
More likely laying
the foundation for a house.
- You're a trusting soul,
aren't you, Doctor?
- Is that a crime?
- No, on the contrary.
I envy you.
- Are you trying
to make me believe
you're one of those
hard boiled reporters
that we read about
or see in the movies?
- No, but working
on a newspaper,
one becomes cynical
and suspicious.
CROW:
Aw, she writes for Crappy Dick.
What a bucket of bolts.
- I've enjoyed meeting you,
Miss Hunter.
I hope to have the pleasure
of seeing you again.
- I have a hunch you will,
Doctor Foster.
TOM:
You have a hunch too?
I guess it's contagious.
- ...just why did you
come up here,
or is it a secret?
- It is, but somehow I feel
that I can trust you.
- You can.
- You've heard of the case
of the vanishing brides?
- Why, surely.
- I think I have a clue.
- You don't mean
that you suspect...
- Yes, I do.
I wanna show you something.
What are these?
- Why, they're orchids,
of course.
- You bet they're orchids.
And they didn't grow
in my dreams.
They're exactly likely the one
that disappeared from my bag.
TOM:
They grew in... [indistinct].
- I found them on the floor
beside my bed this morning.
The person who came
into my room last night
must've brought these with him.
That seems like
a logical explanation.
- There's
no question about it.
Honestly, Doctor,
don't you remember
meeting me in the hallway
last night.
- No, I don't.
And if I did I--
I must've been asleep.
- Either that,
or you were hypnotized.
- Yes, that's quite possible.
CROW:
He may still be.
TOM:
[indistinct].
JOEL:
Looks like a train,
but he'll need proof.
- Well, watch your step.
And if you discover
anything, call me.
- That's a promise.
- Goodbye.
- Not goodbye, au revoir.
CROW:
No, not au revoir, ciao.
No, not ciao, aloha.
No, not aloha, aufiderzein!
- Alright,
print the story on page one.
[JOEL MUFFLED SPEECH]
- ...fingers crossed
that this paper
isn't sued for libel
by some of these phony suspects
that the police
are bringing in.
[JOEL MUFFLED SPEECH]
...get me a [INDISTINCT] outta
the guy they just brought in.
- I don't want photographs.
I want real clues.
If the DA's office
can't pick up the madman
who's stealing the bodies
of these dead girls,
maybe we can.
- Okay, I'll throw it
in the wastebasket.
JOEL: The script?
- No, have it developed.
[indistinct]
Where's Lefty?
- Over at Central Station.
- The only thing
he gets over there
is a game of gin rummy.
Tell him to get back here.
- Well, I got something.
- I'll say you have,
you're fired.
- What do you mean?
You can't do that to me.
- Listen, just because
the bodies of dead girls
disappear
is no reason
you can do a vanishing act.
- But you gave me
the assignment.
Yeah, I suppose I did.
Alright,
where have you been?
What've you uncovered?
- Well, hey, not so fast.
Listen, Mr. Keenan,
last night I went through
the most gruesome
experience of my life.
- You should talk.
All of my life
has been a nightmare.
- Well, you can rest easier now,
because I've seen plenty.
If I can only prove
I wasn't dreaming.
- Dreaming?
- I had a dream
last night myself.
I dreamed you gave me that raise
you been promising me.
TOM:
Thank you, Shecky.
- ...go on with
your dream story.
- Well, there's a certain
Professor Lorenz
that lives upstate.
He knows all about orchids
but insists that he doesn't
grow them anymore.
Yet, I found these
in my bedroom this morning.
- Listen [indistinct]
you didn't go off someplace
and get married, did you?
- No, I didn't.
But I saw the bodies
of those other missing brides.
- Alright.
Now take it easy.
Stop breathing hard, Pat,
and tell me all about it.
Did you really see
any bodies?
- Yes, and no.
- I see.
Just a bit of ectoplasm.
JOEL:
Yeah, on the front
of your jacket.
- ...only...
Oh, I can't explain it.
- Yeah, you know something
the same way I am.
I see brides everywhere,
hear wedding bells
ringing in my ears.
- And I saw a dead man too.
ALL:
And his hair was perfect!
- Very well.
JOEL:
Hubba, hubba, what a suit.
Let me clean that off.
- ...I'm sorry.
She's busy,
she's with Mr. Keenan.
- It's very important
that I see her.
I'm Dr. Foster.
I wonder if you'd mind
announcing me.
TOM:
And now, right here
in our very office,
a very talented young Doctor,
please welcome...
- ...insists on seeing
Miss Hunter.
- Tell him he can have
all of her time from now on.
- That's the Dr. Foster
I was telling you about.
Maybe he has more evidence.
- Alright,
send the saw bones in.
- Hey look,
if you don't mind,
I'm going out
for a nervous breakdown.
TOM:
Funny!
- Well Doctor,
you almost beat me here.
- Yes, I drove down.
- Dr. Foster,
Mr. Keenan, my editor.
- Very nice to meet you,
Mr. Keenan.
- How do you do?
This cub reporter of mine
has been telling me
a weird story
about a certain Dr. Lorenz
up in your neighborhood.
- It's weird alright,
but I'm confident it's true.
After you left,
I looked around the station
to find out if Lorenz
had any other coffins
assigned to him.
I found the consignment alright,
but instead of a coffin,
it was a box
filled with this stuff.
CROW:
Olive loaf.
- So what?
That's ordinary garden moss.
- It's moss, alright.
But not ordinary.
This is a special type
used by florists
and hybridizers
for growing orchids.
It's called ozmondin.
ALL [MUMBLING]:
Ozmondin?
- ...he does grow orchids
like these.
And the same kind were worn
by every one of the brides
that died.
- Well, maybe it is a clue.
But how do I know that the rest
isn't a cockeyed nightmare?
CROW:
Or a night-eyed cock-mare.
- ...you don't remember
talking to her.
- I could've talked to her
while in a somnambulistic
state,
under the influence
of hypnotism.
- Aw, now wait a minute.
Are you trying to tell me
that this Professor Lorenz
is a hypnotist
as well as a horticulturist?
JOEL:
And a ventriloquist.
- My short acquaintance with him
has convinced me
that he's a man
of unlimited talents.
He's strange, peculiar.
I've even suspected him
of being insane.
But the fact remains,
he's not only a doctor,
but a physicist and a scientist
of great ability.
TOM:
And a horticulturist.
- ...this hotheaded wife of his?
- I hesitate to bring her
into the case at all.
Professional ethics
forbid a doctor
talking
about his patients.
- Oh, forget about
your ethics, Doctor.
After all,
we're after a criminal.
How does this woman
fit into the picture?
Come on...
JOEL:
Just clearing him up
a little bit there.
- ...curious fact about her is
that although she has
the appearance of a young woman,
her heart and arteries
indicate
that she's at least
70 or 80 years old.
- Well, that doesn't
explain anything.
It certainly
doesn't explain why...
TOM:
It's tidy, now.
- ...should steal
these dead girls.
JOEL:
Nice and clean.
- It's possible
they may still be alive.
- Alive in a cataleptic state?
TOM:
Iowa?
- Alright, alright.
What are your other deductions?
- Simply this.
These young girls,
whether dead or alive,
are being used by Lorenz
in some manner,
as human guinea pigs
to sustain his wife
in a youthful state.
TOM: Bride juice.
- Oh, that's preposterous.
- It's nothing of the kind.
Scientists are finding out
every day
that glands and hormones
have a lot to do
with life and health.
JOEL: Yeah!
- The glands in our bodies
help determine
the condition of our teeth,
the texture of our hair...
CROW: The cut of our jib.
JOEL: Learning is fun.
- ...I wouldn't dare print
such a fantastic story.
- I bring you the biggest
story of the year
and a chance to get
this newspaper a real scoop,
and you call it fantastic?
- Alright, I'll put Doyle on it
to track it down.
- I'm afraid
you won't get very far.
Professor Lorenz
is a clever man.
Clever enough to withstand
any investigation
and destroy any evidence.
- Why not track the fella?
- How?
- Well, he steals
dead brides, doesn't he?
- Aw, now look, Pat.
Do you want to be
a June bride?
- Well, sure.
I mean, that is, no, not yet.
JOEL: Oh.
- Anyways, Lorenz knows me.
- Alright,
then stop talking nonsense.
This paper can't assume
the responsibility
of such a harebrained scheme.
- Oh, please, Mr. Keenan.
You can't pass up
an opportunity like this.
[♪♪♪]
CROW [WOMAN'S VOICE]:
Cigars, cigarettes, tiparillos?
- Give me a bourbon with soda.
- There she is.
- Cigarettes?
- Eh, she's cute.
CROW:
Well, if you're into
that sort of thing.
- Well, would you like to dance?
- Later. Business
before pleasure, you know.
JOEL:
Do you really think
it'd be a pleasure
to dance with him?
- Miss Woods, Dr. Foster.
- Good evening, Miss Woods.
- How do you do?
- I've something important
to tell you.
- I'm all ears.
- Let's go
to your dressing room.
- Okay.
- I won't be long.
- Alright.
JOEL:
Let's powder our noses.
- Peggy, I've landed
a good part for you.
A chance to prove your talent.
- Really? What is it,
a picture or a play?
JOEL:
Call girl.
- My paper's going to
stage a phony wedding
and we want you to be
the perfect June bride.
- Now wait just a minute...
- With bride's maids and flowers
and all the trimmings.
- What is it?
A circulation stunt?
- No.
You've heard of the case
of the vanishing brides.
- Sure.
- Well this is a plan we had
to track the person...
CROW:
What is it?
- ...who's been stealing
their bodies.
- Are you kidding?
- Certainly not.
The job will pay you plenty.
- How'll I collect
if I'm dead?
- You won't be dead.
All you have to be careful of
is not to smell any flowers.
- All I do is lie
six feet underground
and push them up, nix.
Count me out!
- Listen, Peggy.
I'm offering you a chance
to get your picture
on the front page
of every newspaper
in this country.
CROW:
And in the obituary.
- ...Broadway producers
and Hollywood studios
will be offering you contracts.
Why, it's the chance
you've been waiting for!
TOM:
That's really a load of hooey.
[GROANS]
CROW:
And there she is.
- She's the most unusual type.
JOEL [IMITATES LUGOSI]:
She's just my type, B-positive.
- She'd make a charming
addition to our family.
- June 20th.
- A date we shall not forget.
JOEL [IMITATES LUGOSI]:
A date that will live
in infamy!
[SINISTER LAUGH]
- Fagah, what are you doing
in this part of the house?
TOM:
What'd he call her?
- I keep hearing my son's voice
calling for me.
- Your son is better off
where he is.
Go back to your work.
- Master,
you shouldn't have done it.
He didn't deserve to die!
- Do what I say
and don't come up here again!
CROW:
Or it's community theatre
for you, babe.
- Yes, Master.
TOM:
Lorenz Leachman,
ladies and gentlemen,
give her a big hand.
Lorenz Leachman.
- Well, everything's all set.
She's young and pretty.
- Yeah.
What assurances have we
that this Lorenz guy
will show up
to make the snatch?
- And what happens if he does
kidnap this fake bride?
- Well, the private chapel
and the neighborhood
will be covered
with guards and well,
Lorenz hasn't
a chance to escape.
- Providing he shows up.
And if he doesn't,
I'm sucker and out 500 bucks.
- And if he does,
you have an exclusive story
with big juicy headlines.
JOEL:
Big, tender, sloppy headlines.
Slathered with sauce.
Chomp.
Juicy to a fault.
- Well, blushing bride,
here's where you go on
for your big scene.
- Or big flop.
My knees are shaking.
- There's nothing
to be afraid of.
Here's your bouquet
and the phony orchids.
Now don't forget
to put on your hat.
- Leave that to me.
You got plenty of
photographers out there?
- Certainly.
- And what about the cops?
- How many times
do I have to tell you?
Nothing's going
to happen to you.
- Oh, Miss Hunter.
- Yes?
JOEL: Doesn't smell weird to me.
- Uh, I wanted to ask you.
In this ceremony, shall we use
the word "cherish" or "obey?"
- You mean, for the bride?
- Yes.
- Well, just for this once,
let's put the old fashioned
word in, "obey."
- I've marked the words here.
Just read the ceremony
slowly, solemnly.
- Yes, I understand.
- I hope what you're doing
isn't wrong.
- It's all in good cause.
- Well, I suppose it is.
Well, if you need me,
you'll find me in my study.
- Thank you.
You've been grand, Reverend.
CROW:
And really creepy.
- What do I do now?
- Just march down the aisle
and don't forget to faint
at the altar.
- Well, here goes nothing.
TOM:
And the rest of the film.
- How's everything going?
- Alright so far, I guess.
- Good.
- Ceremony's about to begin.
- I certainly hope
somebody shows up
besides these
ham actors I'm paying.
- You know, it seems to me
that if Lorenz
were ready to strike,
he'd have sent an orchid.
- Just a minute...
JOEL:
Hey, it's Lee Harvey Oswald,
you guys.
- Did you say orchid?
- And I'll take you with it.
JOEL:
Oh, they nabbed him.
- There you are.
TOM:
Well, there's a second actor
theory.
- It looks like you're right.
CROW:
No actors in this scene.
[PIANO NOTES]
TOM:
They just don't look
conspicuous enough, do they?
JOEL:
They're the mother and father
and father of the bride.
TOM:
Ah.
CROW [CRIES]:
So sad.
[TOM AND CROW CRYING]
JOEL:
Hey, come on.
It's not a real wedding,
you guys.
Don't cry.
CROW:
We know, it's the script
that's upsetting us.
JOEL:
Mmm-hmm.
It's the Notre Dame
fight song.
CROW:
He makes a lovely bride.
- It looks just like
a real wedding, doesn't it?
- Yes.
Too bad it isn't...
ours.
- Is that a proposal,
Dr. Foster?
CROW:
It's the best I can do,
you know I can't gesture.
JOEL:
He asked me!
- ...speak to you
in his study, Miss Hunter.
- But...
Oh, you mean,
the real Minister.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Thank you.
I'll be right back.
TOM:
Oh man, did I really
just ask her to marry me?
What was I thinking?
- You wanted to see me,
Reverend?
[TOM GROANS]
[SCREAMS]
JOEL:
It's the sleeper,
and that's illegal
submission hold.
CROW:
Two points.
- Where's Pat?
- Minister sent for her.
JOEL:
Well, what's he gonna do,
his horticulture, hypnotism,
or ventriloquist act?
TOM:
Oh, probably ventriloquism.
Always a crowd pleasure.
JOEL:
She's in the right position
for it.
CROW:
Say hello to the folks, Bobby.
Hello, Bobby, hello.
- I'll be right back.
JOEL [IMITATES LUGOSI]:
She'll be perfect
for my experiments.
CROW:
She's acting
a little wooden.
- Oh Pat?
TOM:
Everyone on stage
for the big Cossack number.
Five minutes.
JOEL: Hmm?
CROW:
What the...?
Cheap door.
TOM:
A midget in a stairwell.
You can't really
get much shorter than that.
CROW:
He makes it seem
like we're in an airplane.
[♪♪♪]
JOEL:
There's that
Laurel and Hardy music again.
[GUNSHOT]
TOM:
Oh1 Nice shot.
CROW:
Trying to kneecap Bela.
- Please, Master!
Don't leave me.
JOEL:
Oh, that's cold.
Oh great, Tony.
You shot a midget.
I hope you sleep well tonight.
Real nice.
CROW:
I didn't know.
JOEL:
They got a new
garage door opener.
TOM:
Cloris is the only one left.
JOEL:
It's the old fashioned
kind of garage door opener.
TOM: An old woman?
JOEL: Yeah.
CROW:
Hey, don't bruise the goods.
- Toby, my son.
Where is...
TOM:
Table for one?
- Toby's gone.
He was careless.
- You shouldn't have left.
- [indistinct]
Where's the Countess?
- Waiting, as usual.
- Hurry up. Let's go.
CROW:
She's the worst mother
in the world.
JOEL:
Oh, that's a great lab.
Nice dirt floor,
real sanitary, you know?
[GROANING]
- There was trouble?
- Yes, but we'll be finished
before anyone finds us.
- But the brides.
What will we do without them?
- We have to leave them here.
- Which means I will perish!
- [indistinct]
In the meantime,
we take this one with us.
- What are you waiting for?
JOEL:
He's gotta dress again,
takes a really long time.
- Well, my dear...
CROW: He looks good
for being in a truck,
in a bag.
JOEL:
Nice quaff.
- I would have preferred
that you would be a bride,
but it really doesn't matter.
You'll serve our purpose
just as well.
- Now both of my sons are gone.
You betrayed me, Master.
[GASPS]
JOEL:
That's the price you pay
for being
a sideshow pass around.
- I have work to do.
TOM:
He's really not a good man.
Turn off The Little Rascals
Music too.
JOEL:
Time for the ear piercing.
CROW:
Get that paper punch.
TOM:
It just never heals well
with a dead person.
CROW:
Hey Cloris, what's up?
Oh yikes!
- No! No!
- You betrayed me, Master.
You shouldn't have done it.
CROW:
He got the point.
TOM:
Due to the nature of this film,
no one will be admitted during
the tragic punching scenes.
[MOANING]
CROW: Hey, you've got a...
TOM: You've got something...
...on the corner of your mouth,
you might want to get that...
yeah...
CROW:
Why you... I oughta...
JOEL [IMITATE LUGOSI]:
These frat parties are awesome!
I'm wasted.
- You stay here
and cover this room.
CROW:
Quick, everybody up here.
- Your hand is unsteady.
TOM:
Of course it's unsteady,
I've just been stabbed
by a second rate
character actress.
[GROANS]
CROW:
Quick, through here everybody.
And in through here.
Down here.
Right.
In through here.
[SCREAMS]
CROW:
Nice swoon.
- Pat!
Pat?
- Is she dead?
- No, just scared to death.
[SIGHS]
- Alright, break it up.
We've got headlines to write.
- Do I get a byline?
[CHUCKLES]
- After this,
you can have a clothesline
with my shirt on it.
JOEL:
That old clothesline joke.
- I now pronounce you
man and wife.
JOEL:
And man.
- Finally make
a newspaper woman out of you
and then
you have to go and quit.
- And to think that
this was the cause of it all.
[LAUGHS]
TOM:
[indistinct].
JOEL:
We better get out of here.
I sense...
[ALL YELLING]
- Okay, it's that time.
It's the end of the movie
and it's time for
some ram chip action, okay.
- Wow!
- You know what to do,
Tom Servo,
why don't you tell us
about it buddy?
- Okay, Mr. Patronize.
We say something good
about the movie
and something bad
and then we get a ram chip.
Right, To Sir With Love?
- Yeah, and I think
I'm going to start with Crow
while you adjust
your attitude, alright?
Okay Crow, give me
a good thing about the movie,
give me a bad thing
about the movie.
- Good thing
about the movie was,
we got to meet an entire
family of mutants.
- Right, and the bad thing?
- Bad thing was,
they're so stupid
they tried to commit
inconspicuous murder
on the most conspicuous day
of a woman's life.
- You, my friend,
get a ram chip.
- Ah!
- There you go, alright, good.
Oops, fell out there.
Okay, anyway, Tom Servo.
Now, tell me a bad thing
about the movie.
- Well, it was painfully long,
the color was nonexistent,
it was a bad print,
it was really hard to watch
Bela Lugosi's
already mediocre career...
- Okay, okay, that's good...
- ...total obscurity...
- Okay, that's good.
Now just give me a good thing.
- A good thing...
hmm... um...
- Get a ram chip.
- Um...
- Just give me
a good thing, pal.
What's wrong?
Can't you think of
a good thing about the movie?
- A good thing...
something is wrong...
[PANTING]
Easy...
- Whoa!
- Oh, man.
Crow, you gotta go
get my tools.
Tom Servo is toasted.
This one's fried.
Anyway, scientists,
what'd you think of that one?
- Hey, it blew up one of
those little drone things.
I'll make a note to get
more movies just like that.
- Yes.
Here Larry, file this.
- Yeah.
- Well, bye for now,
my little space biscuit.
[♪♪♪]